So how can we fix this problem? Well, the first thing
那么我们如何解决这个问题呢？
we should think about is, well, can we give a base case.
我们应该考虑的第一件事是 我们可以给一个基本案例嘛?
All right. All of the recursive definitions we had. We had a
好了 我们所有的递归定义都会有终止的方式
way of stopping. So, we had a base case. Right. With, factorial,
所以 我们有一个基本情况 关于阶乘 我们说 我们要预先定义
we said, we are going to pre-define, that we know the value
当输入为0时 我们应当知道阶乘的值
of factorial when the input is 0. We know that the value
我们直到值应该为 1
is 1. We are not going to define it, in terms of factorial.
我们将不会定义它 根据阶乘
We are going to note it's value. We did this for palindrome we
我们将标注它的值 我们之前说的回文也是这样做的 我们有一个基本情况
said, palindrome, we have a base case, when the input
当输入字符串是一个空字符串
string is an empty string, it's predefined as a palindrome We
它被预定义为回文
don't have to do anything else. And we did this
我们不需要做任何其他事情
for fibonacci, where we had two bases cases? But for all
我们对斐波那契数列也这样做 它有两个基本情况
these definitions, we had some starting point, that was not
但对于所有这些定义 我们有一些起点
defined in terms of thing we are defining. And that's why
没有根据我们定义的事情而被定义
it was good recursive definition, because we had the base case.
这就是为什么它是好的递归定义 因为我们有基本情况
We don't have one here. So let's try to invent one.
我们在这里没有 所以让我们尝试构建一个
Let's suppose that we made our base case. So if
让我们假设我们构建了我们的基本情况
we're going to fix this, what we need to do
所以如果我们要解决这个问题 我们需要做的
is invent a base case. Maybe that will solve our
是构建一种基础案例 也许这将解决我们的问题
problem. So let's try and add a base case. So.
所以让我们尝试添加一个基础案例
Suppose we assume we know the popularity of Alice and
所以假设我们知道爱丽丝的人气得分
sadly Alice is not very popular. Her popularity score is
忧伤的是爱丽丝不是很受欢迎 她的流行度分数是 1
a 1. So that looks like a base case, right
所以这看起来像一个基础案例
we define the base case for factorial for 0 for palindrome
我们定义阶乘的基本情况为 0 回文的基本情况为空
for space. Let's pick Alice as our base case
现在让我们选择爱丽丝作为基本情况
now. And. That works like this for the mathematical
数学定义是像这样的
definition. For the python code, what we would need
对于python代码 我们需要做的是
to do is add the base case, as in a
在语句中添加基本案例
statement. So we would insert a line here that
所以我们在这里插入一行
says that if p is Alice, return Alice's popularity
说如果p是Alice 返回Alice的人气得分
score which is our base case which is 1.
就是我们的基础案例 1
So this looks more like the recursive definitions we've seen.
所以这看起来更像我们看到的递归定义
Now we have a question. See if this
现在我们有一个问题 看看定义是否有效
actually works. So the question is, would this definition
所以问题是 定义可以工作嘛?
work? The possible answers are, only if everyone
可能的答案是
is friends with Alice, only if no one is
只有当每个人都是爱丽丝的朋友
friends with Alice, only if, from every person
只有没有人是爱丽丝的朋友
in the network,. There's some way that you can
只有从网络中的每个人都有某种方法
follow links that eventually reaches Alice. Only if there
可以跟随链接 并最终与爱丽丝相连
are no cycles in the graph. So there's no
只有在图表中没有循环时
way to start from one person and end
所以没有办法从一个人开始
up at the same person by following friendship's, by
并通过跟随友谊关系的链接
following friendship links. And the final choice is no,
在同一个人结束 最后的选项是没有
that there's really no situation where this works well.
在任何情况下 它都不会有效